<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://blog.nakam.org/journal</id>
    <title>nakam journal</title>
    <updated>2024-08-09T01:22:03.046Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://blog.nakam.org/journal"/>
    <subtitle>A daily journal from nakam blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://blog.nakam.org/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>nakam.org</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024-08-09 Daily Journal]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.nakam.org/journal/20240809-daily-journal</id>
        <link href="https://blog.nakam.org/journal/20240809-daily-journal"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T01:22:03.046Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looks like I am on a streak. Third post within two days. There has been a major earthquake in Kyushu. Fortunately, we didn't feel anything in Tokyo and all the friends and family members are keeping safe.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looks like I am on a streak. Third post within two days. There has been a major earthquake in Kyushu. Fortunately, we didn't feel anything in Tokyo and all the friends and family members are keeping safe.</p>
<p>Tachan's first birthday is approaching and we are (mostly Maiko) deciding on what cakes to buy and about the decoration items as well. The primary cake has blueish hue and a brown bear (edible) on it and second one is a chocolate cake (again with a brown bear on it). Tachan can't eat chocolate as of now.</p>
<p>Oh well, today I met (online) two colleges from our US office. We mostly talked about how to bootstrap a system at our company. The bootstapping stucture we have is a mess as of now because we are transitioning from legacy cluster and until we move off them, all the changes to the bootstrapping repo needs to be fully backward compatible. There were some major changes in how we handle new and legacy clusters, so it has become a major pain to sustain them together, at least for the end users - as the API we provide them for bootstrapping isn't very clean and intuitive.</p>
<p>Any about the earthquake again, Meteorological Agency has issued "huge earthquake warning". This is gonna be a scare big weekend.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Poswal Umesh</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/nakamume</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="2024-08" term="2024-08"/>
        <category label="2024" term="2024"/>
        <category label="journal" term="journal"/>
        <category label="daily" term="daily"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024-08-08 Daily Journal]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.nakam.org/journal/20240808-daily-journal</id>
        <link href="https://blog.nakam.org/journal/20240808-daily-journal"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T08:56:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today has been a rollerposter of unexpectedness. At work I was working on a proposal to implement a mechanism to prevent normal pods  from scheduling to our K8s clusters before all of our critical daemonsets are ready. I drafted the proposal yesterday and presented it today. It went fine as is. It was pretty simple actually. We decided to use startupTaints on our Karpentor nodepools for each required daemonset and then made the daemonset responsible for removing the said taint ones it becomes ready.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today has been a rollerposter of unexpectedness. At work I was working on a proposal to implement a mechanism to prevent normal pods  from scheduling to our K8s clusters before all of our critical daemonsets are ready. I drafted the proposal yesterday and presented it today. It went fine as is. It was pretty simple actually. We decided to use <strong>startupTaints</strong> on our Karpentor nodepools for each required daemonset and then made the daemonset responsible for removing the said taint ones it becomes ready.</p>
<p>As for the personal stuff, I wanted to start with a blog where I could write freely (without going into much details of the things) and about my daily life, routine. I've set up a docusaurus blog previously. I spent some time checking if the <strong>mdbook</strong> would be a good fit this daily journal blog. I fired up a test mdbook book and compared it with docusaurus style blog I had. Docusaurus style felt good to eyes (it looked nice) - so I decided to stick with docusaurus and started a second blog on same docusaurus instance. If you are reading this - you know how to reach this daily blog. I call it <em>daily blog</em> but I might not write up daily. As of now though, I feel pretty motivated to write frequently, maybe couple of time a week <!-- -->😀</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Poswal Umesh</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/nakamume</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="2024-08" term="2024-08"/>
        <category label="2024" term="2024"/>
        <category label="journal" term="journal"/>
        <category label="daily" term="daily"/>
    </entry>
</feed>